Nitheesh S

Web Developer

15/11, F6, Rohini homes, 1st main road, Kumaran nagar, Chennai - 92

+91 8608790838 nitheeshmsk@gmail.com https://github.com/Nitheesh-S

About Me

I'm a web developer with 3 years and 6 months of experience. Learning how successful large scale products work under the hood, never ceases to amaze me.

Technical Skills

Backend: Django, Python, Mysql, Electron.js (Nodejs),

Frontend: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, SASS, css

DevOps: Worked on developing apis for email and file uploading to Azure and Google Cloud.

Open to involving in: Nodejs, Go and many more.

Experience

Software Engineer / Iderize

JAN 2020 - PRESENT, CHENNAI

Working on a serverless golang project.

Executive - UI Development / Shri Harini Media Ltd., (Ramco Group Associate)

Sept 2019 - JAN 2020, CHENNAI

- Created a search app with filter, suggestions and pagination using React and azure search api. (https://www.parentcircle.com/overall-search/)
- Developed a few single page products for kids and parents (Gadget Free Hour, Little learners at home [subscription model]) with **Django** (both frontend and backend).
- Developed APIs for posting Forms and logging user activity.
- Developing admin panel for article and other content management (both frontend and backend) with Diango Template and APIs to interact with forms.
- Integrated flora editor (frontend and backend) in Django and customised it based on requirements.
- Automated deployment process with github actions

- and some bash script.
- Automated build process with github hooks.

Executive Web Developer / Smart Training Resources

September 2018 - September 2019, CHENNAI

- Revamped parts of the company's website using vanilla js and Jquery.
- Developed an android app for managing faculty's activities using Web View.
- Did front end design for managing faculty
- Revamped SMARTIndia website completely with Pug and SASS.

Front-end Designer / Acoadio

June 2017 - September 2018, CHENNAI

- Did a few pages in whiteheights.com with Pug and SASS.
- Made Datamorphix.ai website in wordpress.
- Created a svg animation of their business model using anime js
 - (https://www.datamorphix.ai/product-overview).
- Used Wordpress to build vikasaclinic.com website and customized the website based on clients requirements that wordpress doesn't support.
- Attended Client meetings to discuss project scope.

Education

Velammal Institute of Technology / B.Tech Information Technology

2012-2016, Chennai

Personal Projects

File Renamer application using Electorn.js (node.js)